Aniruddha Jana

Kolkata, West Bengal, India

aniruddhaj43@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/aniruddha-jana-aj

Summary

I am a pre-final year student studying Electronics and Communication Engineering at VIT, Vellore.

I am interested in learning more about Computer Vision, Machine Learning, and IoT & I want to enhance my knowledge in these fields through internships. I want expertise in the field of Image processing.

Python and C/C++ languages are the programming languages that I use most for making projects.

I have experience of more than 2 years in making machine learning models for various projects. Till now, I have participated in 6 hackathons, out of them I have won two.

I also love teaching the concepts and tricks that I know about a particular subject since I love sharing my knowledge with others.

Experience



Chegg Expert

Chegg India

May 2022 - Present (6 months +)

Freelance expert with the responsibility to provide quality answers to guestions uploaded to our Q&A portal. Questions on the Chegg Q&A portal are uploaded by student subscribers from across the world.



Technical Head

VITMAS

Jan 2022 - Present (10 months +)

I am currently Technical Head of VITMAS, VIT, Vellore, where I have various responsibilities from planning technical events to organizing hackathons. Also, I am monitoring around 200 students in the technical domain of VITMAS, and out of them, I am mentoring around 80 students for educating them, inspiring them, and influencing them in Data Science and Electronics field.



Core Committee Member

VITMAS

Dec 2020 - Present (1 year 11 months +)

Event Coordinator of Ideathon 4.0

graVITas VIT Vellore Sep 2022 - Sep 2022 (1 month)



Student Organizer of COGNITION

VITMAS

Aug 2022 - Aug 2022 (1 month)

My role is to design the whole hackathon process, contributed in making the website of COGNITION, help the participants in any technical difficulties and I was also one of the member in the judging panel of this Hackathon, therefore I helped in the judging rounds.

BSNL Trainee

BSNL LTD

Jun 2022 - Jul 2022 (2 months)

Open Source Contributor

GirlScript Summer of Code

Feb 2022 - May 2022 (4 months)

I have worked as an open-source contributor to various projects from several repositories.

Data Science Intern

LetsGrowMore

Jan 2022 - Feb 2022 (2 months)

Education



Vellore Institute of Technology

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Electrical, Electronics and Communications Engineering 2020 - 2024

🌉 Kendriya vidyalaya

Mathematics and Computer Science Apr 2018 - Mar 2020

Licenses & Certifications

Face Recognition Application using Python - GUVI Geek Networks, IITM Research Park

J46M401b3vWf25189h

Computer Vision with Python - Udemy

UC-0f60c7c2-2870-469d-a02b-a6b16d755f76

Artificial Intelligence In Python - Udemy

UC-89725728-c827-4a71-8776-4f9c32de3c94

Image Processing Onramp - MathWorks

- **★ Signal Processing Onramp** MathWorks
- **◆ Deep Learning Onramp** MathWorks
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning DeepLearning.Al
- Arduino Programming and Hardware fundamentals Hackster.io UC-2d04b7d9-339c-4e84-9a22-711ebb5d21a9
- Getting Started with AWS Machine Learning Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- MySQL Database Development Mastery Udemy
- Certificate of Participation in First Preliminary Round: Online Coding of Optum Stratethon: E-Track Unstop (formerly Dare2Compete)
 90a1a8d5-b9fd-4b32-8d85-b4dd27989a61

Skills

Data Analysis • Technical Support • Project Management • Management • Decision-Making • Telecommunications • Internet of Things (IoT) • Digital Communication • Network Security • Internet Protocol Suite (TCP/IP)

Honors & Awards

Winner of Sponsor Track of Wafflehacks - WaffleHacks

Jun 2022

Best Domain Name from Domain.com

Honorable Mention in Healthcare

Link: https://devpost.com/software/forheart

Winner of Social Impact Track of HoyaHAcks - HoyaHacks

Jan 2022

WINNER Social Impact Track Prize

Link: https://devpost.com/software/13-debug-thugs